<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curatorial Projects on Avani Sastry</title>
    <link>/curatorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curatorial Projects on Avani Sastry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/curatorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Capturing the Subcontinent</title>
      <link>/curatorial/capturing-the-subcontinent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/curatorial/capturing-the-subcontinent/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This installation features photographs of India (later India and Pakistan) from the 1860s to the present day. These works reveal both the seismic political changes of the era and the continuing importance of artistic traditions. Many of these images are painted, staged, or manipulated, undermining the supposed objectivity of photography and elucidating changing ideas about how we understand and value images.
The Curatorial Process This set of objects was installed in three cases in the Arts of India gallery that previously held textiles and miniature paintings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Anatomies</title>
      <link>/curatorial/synthetic-anatomies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/curatorial/synthetic-anatomies/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Synthetic Anatomies features East Asian artworks that idealize, abstract, or distort the body. These manipulations undermine the association between the body and the individual. Instead of acting as portraits, the works explore shared experiences like immigration, war, and the search for enlightenment.
The term “synthetic” refers to “synthesis,” or the act of combining different materials to form a new product, often a man-made alternative to a natural process. These artworks are products of synthesis—the contemporary artists draw on varied resources like traditional techniques, avant-garde movements across Europe and Asia, and their own experiments with form and material.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
