<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current Research on Avani Sastry</title>
    <link>/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Current Research on Avani Sastry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Out of the Struggle Will Come the Wave</title>
      <link>/research/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/book/</guid>
      <description>“From the Black Panthers, Black Power emerged&amp;hellip;We claim a close relationship with this struggle&amp;hellip;When we gather a revolutionary mass, rouse the people, out of the struggle of this giant mass will come the tidal wave of revolutions.” - The Dalit Panthers Manifesto, 1973 The Dalit Panthers Around 1970, poet and anti-caste activist and then-student Raja Dhale went to a tobacco shop to browse books and came upon Time magazine, which had photographs of the Black Panthers on the cover, an initial encounter that would stay with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Don&#39;t Read a Book, You Speak Into It</title>
      <link>/research/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/thesis/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;If the small voice of history gets a hearing at all&amp;hellip;it will do so only by interrupting the telling in the dominant version, breaking up its storyline and making a mess of its plot.&amp;rdquo; - Ranajit Guha, &amp;ldquo;The Small Voice of History&amp;rdquo; The Question of History The preceding quote comes from Ranajit Guha&amp;rsquo;s seminal essay &amp;ldquo;The Small Voice of History,&amp;rdquo; in which he identifies the narrative structure of typical history writing as essentially colonial, statist, and oppressive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
